<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2018 Trevor Williams <phase1geo@icloud.com> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.phase1geo.minder</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <name>Minder</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Minder</name>
  <summary>Create, develop and visualize your ideas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Créez, développez et visualisez vos idées</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Use the power of mind-mapping to make your ideas come to life.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Utilisez le pouvoir des cartes mentales pour donner vie à vos idées.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Quickly create visual mind-maps using the keyboard and automatic layout.</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Créez rapidement des cartes mentales visuelles en utilisant le clavier et la mise en forme automatique.</li>
      <li>Gorgeous themes.</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Magnifiques thèmes.</li>
      <li>Export to PDF, PNG, JPEG, BMP, SVG, OPML, CSV, Markdown, PlainText and Mermaid formats.</li>
      <li>Printer support.</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Support des imprimantes.</li>
      <li>Add notes, tasks and images to your nodes.</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Ajoutez des notes, des tâches et des images à vos nœuds.</li>
      <li>Stylize nodes and links to add more meaning and improve readability.</li>
      <li>Add node-to-node connections with optional text and notes.</li>
      <li>Colorized node branches.</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Branches colorées.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <provides>
    <binary>com.github.phase1geo.minder</binary>
  </provides>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Node Property Sidebar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Barre latérale des propriétés des nœuds</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/phase1geo/Minder/master/data/screenshots/screenshot-node-properties.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Style Property Sidebar</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/phase1geo/Minder/master/data/screenshots/screenshot-style-properties.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Map Property Sidebar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Barre latérale des propriétés de la carte</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/phase1geo/Minder/master/data/screenshots/screenshot-map-properties.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <developer_name>Trevor Williams</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fr">Trevor Williams</developer_name>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/phase1geo/minder/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/phase1geo/minder/issues/</url>
  <custom>
    <value key="x-appcenter-color-primary">#603461</value>
    <value key="x-appcenter-color-primary-text">rgb(255, 255, 255)</value>
    <value key="x-appcenter-suggested-price">5</value>
  </custom>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="violence-cartoon">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-realistic">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-bloodshed">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-sexual">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-desecration">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-slavery">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-worship">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-alcohol">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-narcotics">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-tobacco">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-nudity">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-themes">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-homosexuality">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-prostitution">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-adultery">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-appearance">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-profanity">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-humor">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-discrimination">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-info">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-location">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-gambling">none</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.3" date="2019-05-17">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for creating a visual connection between any two nodes.</li>
          <li>Added ability to show/hide all connections in the map.</li>
          <li>Added support for remembering the last selected child of a node when navigating the map with the keyboard.</li>
          <li>When escape key is used when editing text, editing mode is ended without reverting text.</li>
          <li>Created unique contextual menus depending on what is selected in the mind map.</li>
          <li>Changed Node sidebar tab to Current which shows either the currently selected node or connection.</li>
          <li>Improved link drawing when a node tree is being moved.</li>
          <li>Switched from using GtkFileChooserDialog to GtkFileChooserNative.</li>
          <li>Added support for inserting emoji when editing text in the mind map (use Control-period).</li>
          <li>Improved readability of theme name when the theme is selected.</li>
          <li>Fixed issue where changing a global style was not saved/applied to new nodes.</li>
          <li>Improved copy/paste support of nodes so that copied items can be pasted in other mind maps.</li>
          <li>Added support for dynamically changing to dark mode in the UI if the prefer-dark desktop gsetting is set.</li>
          <li>Removed support for Loki builds.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.1" date="2019-04-10">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixing appdata.xml file omission.</li>
          <li>Removing automatic style apply when the affects is set to certain values.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2" date="2019-04-09">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added Spanish translation.</li>
          <li>Added support for Control-Return/Tab to support adding newlines/tabs in a node's title.</li>
          <li>Improved node title editing support for selection and cursor movement.</li>
          <li>Added support for automatically opening Minder files from Files.</li>
          <li>Added ability to modify styles of nodes and links.</li>
          <li>Changed layouts to be stored on a per tree basis instead of a per document basis.</li>
          <li>Added support for exporting to the Mermaid format.</li>
          <li>Added support for disabling/enabling displaying markup in node title.</li>
          <li>Improved the look of the fold indicators.</li>
          <li>Lots of bug fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.3" date="2018-10-13">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Adding Spanish translation (thanks to Adolfo Jayme-Barrientos).</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout des traductions en espagnol (grâce à Adolfo Jayme-Barrientos).</li>
          <li>Adding support for special character insertion via the Compose key.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout du support pour l'insertion de caractères spéciaux avec la touche Compose.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.2" date="2018-10-09">
      <description>
        <p>Updating French translation.</p>
        <p xml:lang="fr">Mises à jour des traductions en français.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.1" date="2018-09-27">
      <description>
        <p>Bug fix release</p>
        <p xml:lang="fr">Version corrective</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed bugs related to editing unicode characters in map area.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Correction de bugs liés à l'édition de caractères unicode dans la zone de la carte.</li>
          <li>Reduced height of node textbox in sidebar to help alleviate window sizing problems.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Réduction de la hauteur de la zone de texte du nœud dans la barre latérale pour aider à diminuer les problèmes de dimensionnement de la fenêtre.</li>
          <li>Fixed issue with moving a node to a different position within a parent node.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Correction d'un problème avec le déplacement d'un nœud vers une position différente au sein d'un nœud parent.</li>
          <li>Fixed issue connecting a root node to another node.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Correction d'un problème de connexion d'un nœud racine à un autre nœud.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1" date="2018-09-18">
      <description>
        <p>Images now supported!</p>
        <p xml:lang="fr">Les images sont désormais prises en charge !</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for images within nodes.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge des images à l'intérieur des nœuds.</li>
          <li>Added basic image editing support.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge mimimale de la modification d'image.</li>
          <li>Added support for dragging and dropping local and web images.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge du glisser-déposer d'images locales ou web.</li>
          <li>Added support for resizing node width.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge du redimensionnement de la largeur des nœuds.</li>
          <li>Changed cursors when over a task button.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Modification du curseur au survol d'un bouton de tâche.</li>
          <li>Changed location of task and note elements in a node.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Modification de l'emplacement des éléments de tâche et de note dans un nœud.</li>
          <li>Added support for keeping the map from scrolling off screen.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge du maintien du défilement de la carte de l'écran.</li>
          <li>Added support for shift-mousewheel to scroll horizontally.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge de la molette de la souris avec shift pour le défilement horizontal.</li>
          <li>Added support for control-mousewheel to zoom in/out.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge de la molette de la souris pour effectuer un zoom avant/arrière.</li>
          <li>Fixed issue with drawing background when zoom factor was small.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Correction d'un problème avec l'arrière-plan du graphique lorsque le facteur de zoom était faible.</li>
          <li>Custom icons are now stored as a gresource rather than in the file system.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Les icônes personnalisées sont maintenant stockées en tant que ressource gresource plutôt que dans le système de fichiers.</li>
          <li>Other minor bug fixes.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Autres corrections de bugs mineures.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.8" date="2018-08-06">
      <description>
        <p>Support for more export types and bug fixes.</p>
        <p xml:lang="fr">Prise en charge de plus de types d'exportation et corrections de bugs.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for exporting to SVG, JPEG, BMP, Markdown, PlainText and CSV formats.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge pour l'exportation vers les formats SVG, JPEG, BMP, Mardown, Texte brut et CSV.</li>
          <li>Added support for folding all completed tasks in map inspector.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge pour plier toutes les tâches complétées dans l'inspecteur de carte.</li>
          <li>Added support for unfolding all folded nodes in map inspector.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la prise en charge pour déplier tous les nœuds pliés dans l'inspecteur de carte.</li>
          <li>Added Solarized Dark and Solarized Light themes.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">AJout des thèmes Solarized Dark et Solarized Light.</li>
          <li>Changing button display in map inspector.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Modification de l'affichage du bouton dans l'inspecteur de carte.</li>
          <li>Cleaning up Export menu to include a single "Export…" option.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Nettoyage du menu Exporter pour inclure une seule option « Exporter… ».</li>
          <li>Fixing issue where modified node title in node inspector was lost when input focus was changed.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Correction d'un problème où le titre de nœud modifié dans l'inspecteur de nœud était perdu lorsque le point focalisé en entrée était modifié.</li>
          <li>Fixing issue where an entire tree is attached to another tree.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Correction d'un problème où un arbre entier est attaché à un autre arbre.</li>
          <li>Added Czech translation (thanks to Jan Marek!).</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout des traductions en tchèque (grâce à Jan Marek !).</li>
          <li>Added French translation (thanks to Yannick A.!).</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout des traductions en français (grâce à Yannick A. !).</li>
          <li>Added Brazilian Portuguese translation (thanks to btd1337!)</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout des traductions en portugais brésilien (grâce à btd1337 !)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.7" date="2018-07-13">
      <description>
        <p>Initial startup bug fix.</p>
        <p xml:lang="fr">Correction de bug au premier démarrage.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.4" date="2018-07-11">
      <description>
        <p>Search improvements and bug fixes</p>
        <p xml:lang="fr">Amélioration de la recherche et corrections de bugs</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added ability to search within notes.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la possibilité de chercher parmi les notes.</li>
          <li>Added ability to optionally control search criteria within search popover.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la possibilité pour optionnellement contrôler les critères de recherche dans le volet de recherche.</li>
          <li>Fixed screenshots.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Correction des captures d'écran.</li>
          <li>Changed properties header bar icon to a sidebar hide/show icon for clarity.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">L'icône de la barre supérieure des propriétés a été changée en icône de masquage/affichage dans la barre latérale pour plus de clarté.</li>
          <li>Several minor UI improvements.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Améliorations mineures diverses de l'interface.</li>
          <li>Removing deprecated GTK calls.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Suprresion des éléments GTK dépréciés.</li>
          <li>Added ability to double-click on a node to make it editable.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Ajout de la possibilité de double-cliquer sur un nœud pour le rendre éditable.</li>
          <li>Bug fixes.</li>
          <li xml:lang="fr">Corrections de bugs.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.2" date="2018-06-29">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release</p>
        <p xml:lang="fr">Version initiale</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
